Guide to the photograph album Iraq and Kurdistan - compiled by L. Wells of RAF Hinaidi AD.MC.044
Akkasah: Center for Photography (NYU Abu Dhabi)
Iraq and Kurdistan - compiled by L. Wells of RAF Hinaidi
1934-1936
Akkasah: Center for Photography (NYU Abu Dhabi)
Voyager Press. Rare Books and Manuscripts
Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939
AD.MC.044
257 Photographic Prints Contains 257 gelatin silver print photographs, captioned in manuscript buy the officer, mounted with corners onto taupe cardstock leaves separated by web patterned tissue guards. Oblong 8vo. string­tied album, brown cloth boards, measuring approximately 32.5 x 23.5 x 2 cm, front endpaper inscribed L. Wells, whose name also appears captioned to the verso of a group photograph, and in a list of signatures on a photographed RAF menu card. With a illustrated manuscript title page featuring hand trimmed snapshot photographs, and RAF logo cuttings from official stationery. Photographs vary in size, the smallest measuring approximately 4,5 x 6 cm, and the largest approximately 14 x 10 cm, with the exception of one large RAF hospital staff photograph measuring 21 x 16,5 cm. Wear and punctures to boards, otherwise internally in Very Good Condition.
Album of photographs centering on ways of life throughout Iraq, also providing some insight into the presence of the RAF, from Kurdistan to Basra and in between, during the British Mandate controlled administration of the Hashemite Kingdom of Iraq, captured by officer Les Wells while he served with the Medical Service at the RAF General Hospital in Hinaidi as part of the "British Forces in Iraq" RAF Command, circa 1934-36.
Box AD_MC_044
Biographical / Historical
Text from accompanying documentation by Voyager Press.
"Baghdad, RAF Hinaidi, Ser Amadia [Amadiya], Rutbah Fort, Kurdistan, Babylon, 1934­1936. Album of photographs centering on the indigenous ways of life throughout Iraq, also providing some insight into the presence of the RAF, from Kurdistan to Basra and in between, during the British Mandate controlled administration of the Hashemite Kingdom of Iraq, captured in striking snapshot views by officer L. Wells while he served with the Medical Service at the RAF General Hospital in Hinaidi as part of the "British Forces in Iraq" RAF Command.
Oblong 8vo. string­tied album, brown cloth boards, measuring approximately 32,5 x 23,5 x 2 cm, front endpaper inscribed L. Wells, whose name also appears captioned to the verso of a group photograph, and in a list of signatures on a photographed RAF menu card. With a illustrated manuscript title page featuring hand trimmed snapshot photographs, and RAF logo cuttings from official stationery. Contains 257 gelatin silver print photographs, captioned in manuscript buy the officer, mounted with corners onto taupe cardstock leaves separated by web patterned tissue guards. Photographs vary in size, the smallest measuring approximately 4,5 x 6 cm, and the largest approximately 14 x 10 cm, with the exception of one large RAF hospital staff photograph measuring 21 x 16,5 cm. Wear and punctures to boards, otherwise internally in Very Good Condition, featuring several most excellent photographs of the inhabitants.
Officer L. Wells was attached to RAF Hinaidi, employed in a laboratory of the RAF General Hospital at Hinaidi. A medical man, skilled photographer, and somewhat of an artist. Royal Air Force Station Habbaniya was an evolving cantonment called RAF Dhibban during this period, with services such as the hospital being near completion. RAF Habbaniya was fully operational from October 1936 to 31 May 1959. [Air Headquarters was initially situated in the Old British Residency in Baghdad. The officers were accommodated in various messes in Baghdad and the airmen in a compound at Southgate. In December 1928 the Headquarters moved from Baghdad to RAF Hinaidi Cantonment and was located in one block of the original RAF General Hospital buildings. Apart from the Air Officer Commanding's staff mess, all the AHQ personnel were then accommodated at RAF Hinaidi. Under the Anglo­Iraqi treaty of June 1930, the RAF agreed to withdraw from Hinaidi and Mosul within five years of Iraqi Independence. A reduced force was to reside at Sin el Dhibban approximately sixty miles from Baghdad. Construction for the new camp named RAF Dhibban had begun in 1934 and from 1936 flying squadrons were based there. In January 1937 Air Headquarters and the personnel moved from RAF Hinaidi Cantonment to the newly built RAF Dhibban, which was officially renamed RAF Habbaniya on 31 May 1938. The Air Officer Commanding then lived in Air House at Habbaniya.
A chronicle of civilian life in Iraq during the rule of King Ghazi bin Faisal under sustained British colonial influence, the people seemingly unaffected by foreign presence although representing an era of some anti­British sentiment. Nostalgic views of a beautiful Baghdad are followed by a journey north into Iraqi Kurdistan and a tour of Babylon, and complemented with seldom­seen views of Hinaidi and important RAF sites to which the photographer was connected.
Historic scenes in and around Baghdad include civilians peacefully engaged in their trades and long­standing customs, amidst the numerous remains of ancient civilizations, exquisite architecture, and some contemporary development of Western influence including an airport. The golden domes and minarets of the al­ Kadhimiya Mosque, immense ancient stone figures standing unprotected outside the Iraq museum, the Ottoman Qushla clock tower, the Mausoleum of Sheikh Umar Suhrawardi, Bab al­Wastani (Wastani Gate), are some of the sites captured in photographs. All sorts of people appear in snapshot street scenes, including a scribe offering letter writing services from an outdoor table, groups gathered at a traditional tea house or in front of shops, elders and youngsters, Arab women with young children, Bedouins travelling on camels, a copper smith, a snake charmer, and some merchants. Wells is particularly fascinated by a young lady selling fresh chipatta bread with an alluring smile. A scant few photographs are from Basra, so indicated in the captions.
A two ­week leave in 1935 sees the officer to the Ser Amadia rest camp in Iraqi Kurdistan, presenting an opportunity to tour the environs, including Kurdish and Assyrian settlements and villages in the mountainous region. Views of Camp Amadia at the top of a rocky gorge and the means to access it, serve to illustrate just how isolated it was. Also paying a visit to the Kurdish town of Amadia [Amadiya], he photographs the ancient city gate, as well as a lovely view of the dwellings made of stone walls and thatched roofs, one Assyrian home crafted of mere tree branches and leaves, and the old minaret. [Amadia is an ancient mountain top village and Hill station situated along a tributary to the Great Zab river in the Dahuk Governorate of Iraqi Kurdistan and is now popular summer resort.] While in the Kurdistan district, he takes snapshot photos of an Assyrian village called Haisi [more recently known as Haisse] and another called Kulava, as well as Assyrian goat herders and Assyrian wedding celebrations. A sparsely inhabited village located in "Paradise Alley" at the foot of the mountains is lush with vegetation and thus well cultivated, this place being called "Teruanish." At the quaint alpine village Sulav, he observes the waterfall with a dwelling perched at the top of the cliff from which it flows. From Dohuk we find a scarce photograph of a large fortress type of building, seen from the approach. Views of the river Zab include a rudimentary wooden bridge with stone pillars. In these remote parts of northern Iraq, several Kurdish and Assyrian people were met with, and photographed, generally showing their costume and characteristics, their textile works and living off the land. A tour of Babylon's and its prized antiquities consumes three pages of the album and is accompanied by two related ephemeral documents printed in London."
Content Description
Album of photographs centering on ways of life throughout Iraq, also providing some insight into the presence of the RAF, from Kurdistan to Basra and in between, during the British Mandate controlled administration of the Hashemite Kingdom of Iraq, captured by officer L. Wells while he served with the Medical Service at the RAF General Hospital in Hinaidi as part of the "British Forces in Iraq" RAF Command.
Conditions Governing Access
Repository permission is required for access. Please contact Akkasah Center for Photography, akkasah@nyu.edu +971 2628 5531
Iraq; Military/Soldiers; Royal Air Force; Photographic Prints; Landscapes; Voyager Press. Rare Books and Manuscripts
- The front cover of the album 'A Few Impressions of Iraq.', Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref1; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Iraq
- Cartoons captioned The Overseas Daily Mail, the top left of the page is signed by L. Wells., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref2; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  English Writing; Newspaper Clippings; Signatures; Iraq; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers
- The title page for the album 'A Few Impressions of Iraq,' with the Royal Air Force (RAF) medical branch crest on which is written the motto 'Nec Aspera Terrent'., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref3; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Medals/Insignia; Mosques; Religious Sites; Iraq; Camels; Animals; Men; Street Lamps; Women; Architecture; Royal Air Force; Religious Sites
- Views of memorials, bridges, and mosques in Baghdad, Iraq, including the King Faisal Memorial, Maude (pontoon) Bridge, General Maude Memorial, and the Haidar Khana Mosque., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref4; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Bridges; Mosques; Religious Sites; Architecture; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Baghdad, Iraq; English Writing; Monuments/Memorials; Political Leadership; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Water; Streets/Roads; Cars/Trucks; Crowds; Buildings; Officials; Military/Soldiers; Tigris River; Rivers; Statues/Sculptures; Electricity; Street Lamps
- Views of the Khota Bridge, the Iraqi Museum with a lamassu (winged bull of Nimrud) in the courtyard, and streets, including Post office Street, in Baghdad, Iraq., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref5; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Baghdad, Iraq; Bridges; Religious Sites; Mosques; Men; Electricity; Streets/Roads; Clocks/Watches; Signs/Signposts; Women; Girls; Children; Head Covers/Veils; Museums; Statues/Sculptures; Architecture; Buildings; Rivers; Landscapes; Street Lamps; Shops; Tigris River
- Street scenes in Baghdad, Iraq., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref6; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Baghdad, Iraq; Streets/Roads; Military/Soldiers; Royal Air Force; Men; Group Portraits; Uniforms; Buildings; Children; Electricity; Street Lamps; Carriages/Coaches; Cars/Trucks; Transportation; Kiosks/Kushk; Architecture; Furnishings; Fez/Tarboush; Head Covers/Veils
- Views of people and landmarks in Baghdad, including the courts, the clock tower, and mosques., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref7; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Baghdad, Iraq; Clocks/Watches; Canes/Walking Sticks; Facial Hair; Men; Boys; Children; Group Portraits; Mosques; Architecture; Streets/Roads; Regional/National Dress; Street Vendors; Law; Bridges; Buildings; Palm Trees; Electricity
- Street scenes and the airport in Baghdad, Iraq., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref8; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Crowds; Men; Group Portraits; Streets/Roads; Carriages/Coaches; Transportation; Palm Trees; Mosques; Clocks/Watches; Airports; Buildings; Kiosks/Kushk; Regional/National Dress; Street Lamps; Electricity; Cars/Trucks; Women; Facial Hair; Baghdad, Iraq
- From the top left clockwise: A view of the Mausoleum of Umar Suhrawardi, the Zumurrud Khatun Mosque and Mausoleum, date palms, and two views of the Khota (pontoon) Bridge (linked ref158_000012 in Iraq, Egypt, Yemen - compiled by L. Wells)., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref9; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Baghdad, Iraq; Tombs/Mausoleums; Palm Trees; Bridges; Rivers; Tigris River; Buildings; Forest/Woodlands; Mosques; Religious Sites; Cemeteries; Electricity
- From the top left clockwise: The courtyard of the Abdul Qadir Jilani Mosque, Harun Al-Rashid (Hasani) Palace, the gate of a mosque in Exchange Square, and two views of the Bab Al Wastani (Gates of Baghdad)., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref10; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Baghdad, Iraq; Mosques; Religious Sites; Architecture; Palaces; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Doors/Entrances; Forts/Castles; Clocks/Watches; Street Lamps; Electricity; Clocks/Watches
- From the top left clockwise: an aerial view of Baghdad, men at a chaikhana (tea house), a view of Al Rashid Street, and scribes on the street (linked ref158_000008 in Iraq, Egypt, Yemen - compiled by L. Wells.), Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref11; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Baghdad, Iraq; Buildings; Rivers; Bridges; Tigris River; Streets/Roads; Tea/Coffee; Restaurants/bars; Drinks/Beverages; Street Vendors; Electricity; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Men; Group Portraits; Crowds; Architecture; Boys; Children
- From the top left clockwise: a view of the Haydar-Khana Mosque, the Maud (pontoon) Bridge, a rooftop view of Baghdad, and the Sheikh Ma'ruf al-Karkhi Mausoleum., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref12; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Mosques; Religious Sites; Architecture; Bridges; Tigris River; Rivers; Flags; Palm Trees; Tombs/Mausoleums; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Baghdad, Iraq; Buildings; Cemeteries; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Docks/Piers/Jetties; Electricity
- From the top left clockwise: a group portrait of women and children, a man drinking water, people in front of the entrance of the Al-Kadhimiya Mosque, and an aerial view of the Al-Kadhimiya Mosque and surrounding area. Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref13; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Kadhimiya/Al-Kāẓimiyyah, Baghdad, Iraq; Women; Boys; Children; Regional/National Dress; Head Covers/Veils; Group Portraits; Buildings; Mosques; Religious Sites; Doors/Entrances; Water; Men; Street Vendors; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers
- From the top left clockwise: a group portrait of a coppersmith with several children, bedouins riding camels, a group portrait of a family, and a man walking with two mules., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref14; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Baghdad, Iraq; Iraq; Street Vendors; Shops; Men; Children; Boys; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Workers; Camels; Women; Head Covers/Veils; Buildings; Donkeys; Animals; Deserts; Streets/Roads; Tea/Coffee; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Drinks/Beverages
- From the top left clockwise: two boys on a street near the Maude Bridge, a sunset over the River Tigris (from RAF Hinaidi Cantonment), a fruit shop, and an aerial view of Baghdad., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref15; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Hinaidi, Kanun, Baghdad, Iraq; Baghdad, Iraq; Rivers; Palm Trees; Landscapes; Boys; Children; Streets/Roads; Carriages/Coaches; Group Portraits; Transportation; Tigris River; Buildings; Shops; Food; Workers; Street Lamps; Electricity; Palm Trees; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers
- Four corners: A series of portraits of camels and groups of people. Top-center: A group sits in front of a mudbrick building. Bottom-center: Men sitting on upholstered benches in front of a building., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref16; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iraq; Camels; Streets/Roads; Animals; Men; Boys; Girls; Children; Regional/National Dress; Group Portraits; Outdoors; Palm Trees; Restaurants/bars; Women; Dogs; Head Covers/Veils; Cigarettes; Smoking; Electricity; Furnishings
- From the top left clockwise: the Zumurrud Khatun Mosque, a mosque in Basra, a clock tower in Serai, the flooding of the Khota Bridge, a group of fruit sellers, and a snake charmer with a boy., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref17; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Basra, Iraq; Baghdad, Iraq; Shops; Workers; Food; Tombs/Mausoleums; Clocks/Watches; Buildings; Religious Sites; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Mosques; Men; Boys; Children; Group Portraits; Animals
- A series of portraits of men, women, and children of various ages. (Linked (linked ref158_000010 in Iraq, Egypt, Yemen - compiled by L. Wells) (Please note: This material has been digitized in its entirety and contains racist and culturally insensitive remarks.), Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref18; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iraq; Individual Portraits; Group Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Facial Hair; Women; Children; Head Covers/Veils; Canes/Walking Sticks; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Boys; Girls; Countryside/Rural
- Views of Hindiyah Railway Junction, a series of portraits of a woman selling food at the station, and a Babylonian fort., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref19; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Al-Hindīyah, Iraq; Trains; Transportation; Women; Workers; Street Vendors; Food; Individual Portraits; Men; Group Portraits; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Cameras; Head Covers/Veils; Cigarettes; Smoking; Regional/National Dress; Forts/Castles; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Electricity
- A series of group portraits of a food seller named Selima and several children at Hindiyah Railway Junction (linked to AD_MC_030_ref158_000007 in Iraq, Egypt, Yemen - compiled by L. Wells, AD_MC_046_ref29 in Iraq and Kurdistan - compiled by an RAF serviceman, AD_MC_044_ref20 in A Few Impressions of Iraq)., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref20; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iraq; Trains; Transportation; English Writing; Group Portraits; Women; Boys; Children; Head Covers/Veils; Workers; Food; Regional/National Dress
- Scenes of Babylon including the Ishtar Gate, a stone inscribed with Cuneiform and the Euphrates River., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref21; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Hillah/al-Ḥillah, Iraq; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Rivers; Water; Euphrates River; Landscapes; Palm Trees; Women; Girls; Children; Regional/National Dress; Group Portraits; Head Covers/Veils
- From the top left clockwise: the Lion of Babylon, reliefs on the Temple of Marduk (The Ésagila), Nebuchadnezzar's throne room, a group portrait of RAF soldiers at the Babylon Halt train station, and three views of Nebuchadnezzar's Palace., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref22; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Hillah/al-Ḥillah, Iraq; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Signs/Signposts; Arabic Writing; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Men; Group Portraits; Temples; Palaces; Architecture; Trains; Transportation
- From the top left clockwise: two views of the Ctesiphon Arch (Tāq Kasrā), a bungalow at Ctesiphon, a group portrait of British airmen and Iraqis described as "in the orchard", a portrait of Les Wells and a group portrait of British airmen with Iraqi men (including their host) and children at Ctesiphon., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref23; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Ctesiphon, Iraq; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Individual Portraits; Men; Buildings; Architecture; Regional/National Dress; Palm Trees; Countryside/Rural; Facial Hair; Boys; Children; Air Force; Agriculture/Farms; Food
- Views of KLM DC-2 'Nachtegaal' planes and the airport in Baghdad., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref24; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Dutch Writing; English Writing; Baghdad, Iraq; Airports; Airplanes; Transportation; Buildings; Flags; Royal Air Force; Uniforms; Men; Group Portraits; Military/Soldiers
- From the top left clockwise: an Imperial Airways (Handley Page H.P.42 /45 G-AAXE Hengist) plane in Baghdad, a KLM DC-2 aircraft PH-AJU "Uiver" which crashed near Rutbah Fort in 1934 en route to Batavia (Jakarta) Indonesia, a Nairn Passenger Bus at Rutbah Fort, and a view of Rutbah Fort., Circa 1934; AD_MC_044_ref25; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Baghdad, Iraq; Syria; Airplanes; Transportation; Mountains/Hills; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Forts/Castles; Deserts; Flags; Buses; Uniforms; Ar-Ruṭbah, Iraq
- Two views of an RAF plane (a Vickers Valentia) and aerial views of Iraq and Mosul taken from RAF planes en route to Ser Amadia (Amadiya, Iraqi Kurdistan)., Circa 1935; AD_MC_044_ref26; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Airplanes; Transportation; English Writing; Amadiya/Amedi, Kurdistan, Iraq; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Landscapes; Deserts; Buildings; Mosul, Iraq
- Views of the journey to the Royal Air Force (RAF) leave camp in Ser Amadia, Kurdistan; Duhok, the mountain road and Seven Sisters bends, the Mazurka Gorge from Bebadi/Bibad to the camp and the tented camp. Iraq., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref27; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; Duhok, Kurdistan, Iraq; Cars/Trucks; Transportation; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Deserts; Buildings; Streets/Roads; Tents; Uniforms; Men; Group Portraits
- Top-left clockwise: Two men, one riding a horse, a view of Haisi, and houses in Sulav and Iraqi Kurdistan., Circa 1934-1936; AD_MC_044_ref28; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_044)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iraq; Horses; Animals; Men; Individual Portraits; Uniforms; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Mountains/Hills; Landscapes; Buildings; Children; Streets/Roads; Southern Kurdistan, Iraq; Sulav, Kurdistan, Iraq